Each run lives in its own git worktree.
That means parallel runs never collide with each other.
worca builds on this with two scale-out modes.
The first is fleet mode.
It takes one prompt and runs it across many independent projects at the same time.
That's perfect for rolling a fix across every repo you own.
The second is workspace mode.
This one is for interdependent projects.
A master planner figures out the dependency order.
Child pipelines run tier by tier.
And between tiers, worca runs cross-project integration tests to keep everything in sync.
You can shape worca to your team without forking it.
Almost every part of a pipeline is configurable.
Which stages run.
Which agent runs each stage.
Which model the agent uses.
How many loop iterations are allowed.
Even the prompt the agent sees.
Customization happens at three layers.
The template picks the overall shape.
Per-agent overrides tune individual stages.
And the guide you attach at run time enforces a spec that nothing else can override.
worca ships with a set of built-in pipeline templates.
They cover the common shapes of work.
There's a full feature pipeline with planning, review, and testing.
There's a bug-fix pipeline that skips planning.
There's a docs-only pipeline.
And several more.
Each template is a complete recipe.
Stage list.
Agent prompts.
Loop budgets.
Model assignments.
Most of the time, picking the right template is all you need.
When the built-ins don't fit, you can write your own.
Today this is done through settings.
A richer template-authoring experience is coming to the UI.
The pipeline emits a typed event stream.
There are around 80 different event types in total.
Stage starts.
Bead completions.
Test results.
Cost ticks.
Control decisions.
You subscribe to these events through webhooks.
The webhooks are signed for security.
Some subscribers can also push back.
Control webhooks let you pause, resume, stop, or override a decision while the run is in flight.
The UI itself is just one subscriber to this stream.
That's why everything you see in the UI is also available to your own tools.
worca can push run updates into the chat tools your team already uses.
Set up an integration once.
That can be Telegram, Discord, or Slack.
From then on, worca notifies you when something interesting happens.
A plan is ready.
A pull request has been opened.
The run has paused.
A circuit breaker tripped.
On Telegram, those notifications come with inline actions.
You can pause, resume, or stop a run right from the chat.
No need to open the UI.
And from inside a run, agents can reach out to you directly through the notify skill.
For example, an agent might say: "I'm waiting on a clarification, please reply when you can." You can leave the UI closed and still stay in the loop on long-running work.