worca is an orchestrator for your AI coding agent.
It runs your development process step by step.
So the agent always starts with a design document.
It always implements and runs the tests.
It always performs a code review.
Nothing important gets skipped.
Every step runs in a fresh agent.
That agent only sees what it needs to do its job.
The planner sees the request.
The implementer sees the design decisions for one code change.
The reviewer sees the diff to review.
Nothing leaks across stages.
Nothing is missing.
Each agent stays focused.
The full flow runs as a pipeline.
A pipeline is your workflow, written down.
It moves through stages.
Each stage has its own specialized agent.
Each agent gets a prompt tailored to its role.
And it gets a message tailored to the current state of the work.
worca ships with several pipeline templates built in.
You can also write your own.
There are four ways to tell worca what to do.
The simplest is a prompt.
You describe the work in plain language, and the planner takes it from there.
Next up is a GitHub issue.
It carries more structure, and the planner uses it as a brief.
Even richer is a pre-existing plan file.
With that, the planner stage is skipped entirely.
Every later stage works from your plan directly.
The fourth input is different from the first three.
It's called a guide.
A guide doesn't describe the work.
It constrains how the work is done.
Think of an RFC, a migration spec, or a coding standard.
Every agent treats the guide as the highest authority.
If the plan and the guide disagree, the guide wins.
Reading and re-reading source files is the biggest token sink in autonomous coding.
To cut that cost, worca can build a structural knowledge graph of your repository.
The graph captures how your code fits together.
Agents query the graph instead of grepping their way around.
Two engines plug in here.
The first is graphify.
It maps the AST and call structure of your source code.
The second is CRG.
CRG runs in structural mode today, and a richer semantic mode is on the roadmap.
Either way, the graph is advisory.
It never overrides what you asked for.
It just helps the agents find their way around faster.