Let's look inside a single run.
First, the planner reads your task and produces a detailed design document.
Next, an optional plan reviewer audits that plan, before any code is written.
Then the coordinator takes over.
It breaks the plan into small units of work.
We call those units beads.
Each bead gets a complexity tag.
Now one or more implementer agents pick up beads in parallel.
Each one writes the code and tests for its slice.
After that, a tester runs the full suite.
A reviewer audits the diff.
Only then does the guardian commit the work and open the pull request.
Finally, an optional learner extracts insights from the run, so future runs can improve.
Pipelines also define the guardrails.
How many review rounds are allowed?
How many test retries?
How much can a single run cost before it halts?
All these limits live in the pipeline definition.
So the same template enforces the same discipline every time it runs.
Here's the part that makes worca trustworthy.
Governance is not advice.
It's enforced at runtime.
worca installs hooks that gate every tool call and every commit.
The planner cannot write source files.
The implementer cannot commit.
Only the guardian can commit, and only after the reviewer has signed off.
The pipeline cannot drift off process, no matter what the underlying model decides to do.
When things fail, worca self-corrects.
If tests fail, the tester sends the failure back to the implementer, and the implementer tries again.
The same thing happens with review feedback and with plan revisions.
Each loop has a maximum number of iterations.
A circuit breaker watches for patterns that suggest the loop won't converge.
When it sees one, it halts the run before more budget is wasted.
There's also a smarter dial.
If a task keeps looping back, the next pass runs at a higher reasoning level.
Up to a cap you set.
Cost is a real concern.
Every stage logs what it spent.
Every run rolls up a total.
You can see all of it in the UI.
But visibility alone is not enough.
worca gives you three ways to control spend.
The first is the effort cap.
It bounds how high reasoning effort can escalate.
The second is the circuit breaker.
It halts a run when failure patterns suggest you're throwing good money after bad.
The third is the model profile.
You choose which model runs each stage.
Use Opus where you need depth.
Use Sonnet where you need speed.
Route through your own gateway if you have one.
So the question of how much a run will cost becomes a budget you set.
Every action and every artifact is traceable.
The worca-ui web interface gives you the full picture.
Stage progression.
Iterations.
Time spent.
Cost.
Tool calls.
Agent prompts and responses.
Nothing the pipeline does is hidden from you.
Let's get specific about what you can do in the UI.
You can read the generated plan.
You can see how it evolved across review iterations.
You can open any stage and read its agent prompt.
You can also read the dynamic message that agent received.
In other words, you see exactly what worca asked the agent to do.
You can browse the beads the coordinator produced.
You can read the reviewer's verdict and the diff it reviewed.
You can see test output from every iteration, not just the last one.
Cost, time, and tool-call counts are all there, stage by stage.